

oytun-ikiz
/MrChelizt
oytunikiz@hotmail.com
+31 6 27218044
Eligible to work in NL

Highly versatile and experienced Software Developer with a diverse background in Mobile development, R&D consulting and café ownership. And yes, I've tried many things over the years.

While working as a mobile developer I successfully developed an app made with React-native, as well as delivered PoC with Flutter which I learned in a week. With the PoC the startup raised the funding.

I worked as an R&D consultant and developed 40+ projects varying from plastic recycling facility to gluten-free bread recipe. The plastic recycling facility project raised the funding.

With these experiences, I am confident that I am:

- Quick learner
- · Don't take shortcuts
- · Sincerely reliable sidekick
- · Have high standards for my work
- · Think outside of the box whenever necessary

#### Key skills:

- Frontend Development: React, Redux, TypeScript, JavaScript, CSS, HTML
- Backend Development: NodeJS, Express.js
- Mobile Development: Kotlin, React-Native, Flutter
- Database Management: MySQL, MongoDB
- Cloud Services: Firebase, AWS
- DevOps: GitHub Actions, Docker
- Testing: Mockito, JUnit, Jest

# **Work Experience**

#### Mobile Developer @ BIBTI APP

2021 - 2022

Innovative startup focused on empowering women's safety in transportation through a travel companion Mobile App

- Developed a proof of concept (PoC) with Flutter, which I learned within the week, resulting in attracting investment from an investor.
- Collaborated with a technical advisor and learned React-Native and created a survey app, implementing Firebase for authentication, email service, and database functionality.
- Due to the time difference between Turkey and the US, I made the decision to explore new opportunities for professional growth.

### **R&D Consultant @ TARAFTech GmbH**

2015 - 2016

A startup focused on project-based R&D development for small and medium-sized companies.

**My role:** Developing and managing new projects based on customer requirements, while also identifying new market opportunities for companies by analyzing existing patents, identifying know-how, and finding crazy ideas to fill a niche

### Key results:

- Introduced the systematic project approach that involved gathering customer specifications, analyzing portfolios, shortlisting ideas, and conducting detailed research using various resources such as patents, academic research papers, white papers, and technical documents.
- Developed proof of concept models and took customer feedback for revisions to ensure successful project outcomes.
- Designed over 40 different products for various industries.

#### Main projects:

- Cutting disk for angle grinders. The product is in production with high customer satisfaction.
- HVAC components to be used in ships. Redesigned a part for a condenser, potential effect is improving cooling performance.
- Façade material and methodology for heat recycling. Choose the phase changing material and application methodology, which would reduce heating costs.
- Plastic recycling facility. The project raised the funding.
- Gluten-free bread recipe. Made it for my soul.

In Turkey, it is a common aspiration among white-collar professionals to retire at 40 and venture into the world of entrepreneurship by opening a cafe. I got the timing somewhat wrong and opened one as my first business. Taking on the roles of both owner and cook when required, I successfully operated the cafe. I was fortunate enough to sell it just before the pandemic.

## **Dance Instructor @ ISTANBUL LINDY HOPPERS**

2014 - 2022

- Instructed Lindy Hop dance classes for a diverse group of 10-30 students. Learned how to engage and connect with students.
- Provided constructive feedback to students, helping them improve their dance technique and performance.
- Developed tailored lesson plans to accommodate different skill levels and individual learning styles.

# **Education & Certificates**

| Anadolu University, Bachelor's Degree Information and Management Systems | 2019 – 2023    |
|--|----------------|
| Integrify Academy, Full Stack Developer                                  | 2023           |
| Bilgeadam Academy, Java Android Developer                                | 2020           |
| Udacity, Android Kotlin Developer Nanodegree                             | Sep - Dec 2022 |
| UiPath, RPA Associate Training   | 2020           |